<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jahnel Group ServiceNow Blog - Articles</title>
    <description>A blog about ServiceNow</description>
    <link>
    http://blog.jahnelgroup.com/</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Fix Mobile Menu on Service Portal</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;While developing an application for Service Portal, you are provided with  many features “out of the box”. You get an responsive environment with widgets that can be used on several different pages. But what if you need to change some of those  “out of the box” parts? After one of my applications was tested by QA,  I was given a task to change the behavior  of the menu on mobile view.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//Service-Portal-Mobile-Menu</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//Service-Portal-Mobile-Menu</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Good, the Bad, and the Ugly About ServiceNow from a Developer&#39;s Perspective</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years, the concept of “platform” has been growing and become one of the main topics regarding IT Service Management. ServiceNow is one company in particular that has become a big thing in this space. Sure, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.servicenow.com/customers.html#all-customers&quot;&gt;list&lt;/a&gt; of companies using the ServiceNow platform is impressive, but it doesn’t show how many people are actually using or familiar with the platform. What really brought this to my attention is when I mention ServiceNow while talking to people working in big companies. They usually have heard about it and they either know it is being used at company they, or someone else they know work at. With the growing popularity of the platform comes the need for skilled developers. I familiarized myself with the platform, and I built a demo application. This journey taught me various quirks about the platform which I want to share with all the other Developers.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//Good-Bad-And-Ugly</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//Good-Bad-And-Ugly</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Not Fail Your ServiceNow Certification Exam</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Want a foolproof plan to guarantee success on your ServiceNow Certification Exam? Well, this isn’t it, but it’s as close as I can get! I’m not offering any guarantees, but what I can offer is a guide which has been proven successful for both myself and the rest of my team. By the end of reading this post my goal is to have you feeling prepared and confident to go out and crush your ServiceNow certification exam!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//How-to-Not-Fail-Your-ServiceNow-Certification-Exam</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//How-to-Not-Fail-Your-ServiceNow-Certification-Exam</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Beginner’s Insight into the User Interface on ServiceNow</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;As a new developer, working on the platform for about 5 months, these are some of the thoughts I have on the front-end development for ServiceNow. This post is targeted towards people that have just gone through ServiceNow’s Learning Plan, started getting used to the platform, or just generally curious on how ServiceNow approaches interfaces/design. Veterans are more than welcome to expand on ideas that are going to be listed here and give any helpful insight.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//user-interface</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://blog.jahnelgroup.com//user-interface</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
